<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding Letters by Victor Trejo</title>
    <link>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Coding Letters by Victor Trejo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:45:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design patterns you know (but might not be aware of)</title>
      <link>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/design_patterns_you_know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:45:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/design_patterns_you_know/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader,&#xA;As software grows complex and care is given to its structure, design patterns will appear. Sometimes they will be used intentionally and sometimes inadvertently. We might intuitively reach for patterns in our mental repertoire, or we might reinvent a long-known solution for a seemingly new problem. Regardless of our awareness of them, design patterns will show up.&#xA;If we strive to be intentional about the structure of our software, we will be better equipped by being able to recognize design patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of functions and design patterns</title>
      <link>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/functions_and_design_patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:45:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/functions_and_design_patterns/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader,&#xA;I have been thinking about functions and design patterns and how they resemble one another. They emerge similarly and they can be powerful communication tools. What differentiates them and why should we care?&#xA;Stumbling upon a function Let&amp;rsquo;s start by examining some code written in Rust. With it, a chipmunk is keeping track of the nuts surplus it gathers every month.&#xA;// January let nuts_found = 17; let nuts_needed_this_month = 62; let nuts_surplus = { if nuts_found &amp;gt; nuts_needed_this_month { nuts_found - nuts_needed_this_month } else { 0 } }; println!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick feedback</title>
      <link>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/quick_feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://victormanueltn.github.io/codingletters.github.io/posts/quick_feedback/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader,&#xA;It is 1989. You finally reached the last level of Super Mario Bros and your heart is pounding. You have a single life left. You have never faced these obstacles, these pits, yet the adrenaline kicks in and you somehow reach Bowser. You pause. You take a breath. You go for it&amp;hellip; but you miscalculated, a fireball got you. Game over. You have to restart. All over again. From the very beginning&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
